two uninhabited pacific islands one will
be inhabited by 14 british men
while a separate island will be home to
14 british women
will it be brute power or mental
strength
the winds a day
fine
[Music]
one two three
go oh
actually wrapping up a dinosaur we just
caught a prehistoric animal
a woman needs a man like a fish needs a
bicycle
uh i think evidence begs to differ on
that one sure
it's one thing to say that in a nice
air-conditioned office
but i don't think i have ever heard a
feminist point out the inconvenient
truth
that men almost exclusively work all the
dangerous and important jobs that keep
society running
i can survive without a new york times
journalist but i don't think i can
survive without indoor plumbing
electricity or a roof i find it curious
though that feminists love to proclaim
how independent they are from men on
their computers and cell phones
that were invented by man which brings
up the question of equality
that was a topic of discussion in the
jubilee mra video i covered recently
and i avoided it so i could talk about
it in this video
are men and women equal the answer to
that is no
the reason for that is that men and
women are two different things that you
can't compare
one-to-one on their actual value to
society
equal is the wrong word the correct word
is necessary
food and water are not equal but they
are both necessary
each serves its own role the same is
true for men and women
there are things that women are
naturally better at and there are things
that men
are naturally better at when it comes to
raising children
men are far better at setting boundaries
women
are better at emotional development
taught to kids without fathers
they are often all over the place and
can't contain their behaviors
taught to kids without mothers they are
often emotionally dead
what we have seen with feminism though
is an over promotion of women
followed by a complete lack of respect
for what men contribute
and well i think this show is the
perfect example of why feminists cannot
survive in their fantasy world without
man
for those of you who haven't heard this
is the wonderful experiment in gender
equality
called the island with survival expert
bear grylls
14 average men versus 14 average women
on two different pacific islands
for six weeks both groups have their
clothes
two water canisters and some other basic
supplies like three machetes eight
fishing hooks and a first aid kit
they also had two days of survival
training and were not supposed to do any
other practice
so who will be the superior survival
team the men
or the women obviously both teams had a
rough but my experience watching the
show was
yeah men had it difficult but they
worked hard and pulled through
the women however was just a
never-ending story of misery with one
bad thing happening after another
they were clearly not able to survive
without men much to the anger of
feminists who complained about this
season
let's get into the fun but first if you
like the content you see on this channel
then consider making a donation viewer
support is the best way to keep
independent content creators
independent from big tech so your
support is highly appreciated
links to my paypal patreon and subscribe
start pages can all be found
in the description and also don't forget
to support me on all
tech you can find the links to my parlor
page and my bitshoot channel
in the description as well alright so
the first challenge of the island is to
find a beach to set up camp
it's a lot safer to be on a beach where
you can see everything than it is to be
in a forest full of snakes and
crocodiles
let's see how the men handle this
challenge it's 4pm
with only two hours of daylight
remaining the men's priority
has to be finding a safe place to
shelter for the night
paul thinks the group's best option is a
beach
i personally want to just plow on and
make it
i mean it's going to get darker in here
quicker than it is on the beach
paul pushes on despite the group's
growing descent
i found the sea
[Music]
so that was quick a few hours of intense
stress
everyone pushed through and they all
made it on the first day
as for the women their story is a little
bit more complicated and requires more
than a single clip to discuss
their first mistake was that they
decided to split up
so one group's going to go look and one
group's going to stay here
who's in the go group me can i come yeah
you got your whistles
yes i can tell that these women watched
way too much scooby-doo when they were
kids
you never want to split up when you were
in a dangerous situation
even bear grylls says it's a bad idea
splitting up your group
is a high risk strategy the show says
they split up to protect a fire they
made the previous night
by the way we're on day two and the
women only ended up
walking a few hundred feet away from
their drop points also
you can take the fire with you not to
mention
you would either have to move the fire
or make a new one anyway when you found
a new camp
did they think about this for more than
10 seconds however i will be fair and
point out that
some of the women said this was a stupid
idea hold on a minute
you think that you can walk right round
this island
we don't know anything i think this
decision has been made
a little too quickly but they split up
anyway
on this first trip they find a beach
that isn't that great and they come back
so that was all well and good but now
with that success they are a little bit
more
confident about their bad decision and
they split up again
one of their previous dissenters jamie
joins them this time
more desperate than ever to get out of
the jungle the women are sending out
another search party
to find a beach camp seven women
volunteer to join fee on the trek
including furniture maker kate abby fran
and three others
stay behind in their temporary camp to
keep the vital fire alight
if you watch the show what you'll find
with the women is a lot of feminist
notions of independence
you have to understand that the
independence we experience in the west
is a luxury being by yourself in a
survival situation or in any dangerous
situation
is stupid there is power in numbers
the more people you have the more people
you have to fight and solve
problems you also have to understand
that literally no one in civilization
can survive on their own
there may be a couple of outliers but
outside of them
no one is capable of surviving on their
own without using tools or knowledge
that other people have invented or
discovered
true independence is a myth however
i do think it's funny when a feminist
screams about how she is strong and
independent while her ex-husband is
paying her child support and alimony or
she's on welfare
in civilization we rely heavily on the
functioning interactions of people
who have different useful skills if
those systems fail
most of us are screwed if that happens
people are going to find out just how
dependent they are on everyone else
if you want to succeed your goal in life
is to team up with people who survey a
role
that is complementary to yours that's
what works
what doesn't work is trying to do
everything by yourself
just so you can say your independence
independence or self-reliance is not
about doing everything by yourself
a person who is independent is someone
who pulls his own weight
instead of being dependent on the group
to pull his weight for him
that is what we should be striving for
getting back to the show
this is the point where things start to
go downhill for the women
remember how the guys found a beach in a
few hours well
the women are on day two they split up
they found a beach but the search
expedition party gets lost on the way
back
i'm used to being in forests and i'm not
going to be really happy
if people start telling me i'm going the
wrong way the most important thing
is that we go and we go in a straight
line now honestly i have no idea if this
is right but we've made a plan so we've
got to stick to it this is actually the
opposite direction this is we're going
back towards the beach
the expedition party are deep in the
jungle interior
and have mistakenly headed north in the
wrong direction from their temporary
camp
now completely lost they're doubling
back on themselves
now all kinds of problems start
occurring the most
obvious of which is that it's very hard
for beginners to navigate a forest
without walking in circles
and their forester was useless which
means if they are
lucky enough to find a beach they have
to navigate back to the camp
and then navigate back to the beach they
just turned one trip
into three trips making their gamble
three times as hard
problem number two the team who was at
camp basically can't do anything
like work on a shelter so their time is
wasted
in nature you do not have the luxury of
wasting time
if you watch the show you'll see that
downtime is a very consistent problem on
the women's team
but here is the biggest problem in this
event each teen got a doctor
and some kind of medical assistance dr
piers was the doctor for the men's team
and his assistant was barney who is a
paramedic
on the women's team we have dr belinda
and her assistant lauren
who is a nurse the problem is that the
team's only doctor
and only nurse went to go find a beach
while back in camp a team member fran
is dying
my safety response team are assessing 24
year old fran
after five days without anywhere near
enough water
fran has succumbed to dehydration now i
will give fran credit because she did
tell the medical team
not to give her any extra nutrients so
she wouldn't have an advantage over her
other team members
which is pretty brave but i keep
thinking
how could you be so disorganized that
you wouldn't think to keep someone with
medical experience in each group
i understand that they have a medical
staff on call but it still takes a while
to get there and if there is any intense
emergency
then the person who gets hurt is
basically dead
certainly if there was no on-call
medical team this would have been a very
stupid move
so the medical team evaluates fran and
it turns out that she got dehydrated
dehydrated when earlier it was raining
outside
honestly i know this is all hindsight
and backseat driving
but i'm trying to be fair here they had
a massive water canister and a bunch of
improvised bamboo cups
it's not too much of a stretch to put
some of those cups outside and have them
collect water for you
this is the first instance of several
that the women get saved by the medical
team
to which i will say the men never had an
injury so severe that they
absolutely had to be saved by the
medical staff one got stung by a
non-lethal scorpion
they called the medical team for it but
he would have been fine
the second was will who fell and
ruptured a tendon in his arm
will was evacuated from the island so he
wouldn't permanently damage his arm
but if he had no outside help he would
have survived the women however were
saved
multiple times by the medical staff
which i will get to but let's continue
with the story
the situation with fran gets resolved
and the expedition party still has not
gotten back after like three days
convinced they're close to camp georgie
and lauren go ahead
to recce their surroundings we're just
looking
we're back to where we are no
way can't be we are
the expedition party have spent all day
in the searing heat
only to find they've walked in one big
circle
back to coconut beach
[Music]
so the camp party decides to go search
for the expedition party
and they do the one extremely obvious
thing that the expedition party could
have done
which was follow the coastline the women
at camp
are finally taking their fate into their
own hands
they haven't found us so we've got no
alternative but to find them because
we've stayed and we waited
i don't even know two days three days to
be rescued
now we have to just go and blow our
whistles madly to see if anyone's
hearing us and that's what we're going
to do that's the plan
unaware of the expedition party's
whereabouts the five women
are searching the coastline after
everyone got off the boat
they didn't actually make it that far
into the forest and yes
everyone knew that because of the first
search party all the women who got lost
would have had to do
was walk the coastline and blow their
whistles and they would have easily
found the camp
and i say easily because the camp party
was able to find the expedition party
within a few hours of walking the
coastline
even if they walked the wrong way it
probably wouldn't have taken more than
a day just for comparison i will point
out that at the end of the show
two men kyle and sam got lost in the
forest
at night and were still able to make it
back to camp in the same day
i will also point out that the fire the
women were trying to protect
went out making the whole reason they
split up completely pointless
eventually they find a beach to camp on
after like a week
meanwhile the men have their entire camp
set up
however credit where credit is due the
women did make a fire on the first day
and the men didn't make one until day
two
[Music]
[Applause]
i don't want to sound too cocky too
early i don't think we should i don't
think we should at all
but right now this is
we're winning although once the men's
fire is made
it never goes out the entire six weeks
the women's fire however goes up
multiple times and they could not
restart it
this leads us to the second time the
women had to get saved
the women have now been without water
for more than 48 hours
and they are dangerously dehydrated
their situation
is now beyond critical medical advice is
that the castaways are now
so critically dehydrated that within a
few hours
their lives will genuinely be in danger
so really
i've got no choice but to intervene and
the women
will be given a working bow drill set so
we have women cheering about how they
are doing
better than the men by making their
first fire so quickly
but shortly thereafter in the first week
one of their team members fran
would have died without medical
assistance and by week two
their whole team would have died of
dehydration because they didn't have
a fire for reference you can survive
about three days without water
but keep in mind that they are on a
tropical island that is commonly over 85
degrees fahrenheit
dehydration is a reoccurring problem for
the women
now i haven't mentioned this but anyone
is allowed to leave the island
anytime they want at this point 3 out of
the 14 men have left voluntarily
and 2 out of the 14 women are gone one
voluntarily
and fran from earlier was evacuated
because of medical issues
both teams ended up losing four people
by the end of six weeks
so they were even on that that being
said
let's move on to the next issue there
are multiple cases in the show
where things are just given to the women
and the women take no initiative to grab
it
this brings us to nature's biggest
handout in the show
which are two piglets that just walk
onto the women's beach camp
hello all they've eaten in a week
are a few handfuls of yucca and coconut
we've got two of the cutest little
piglets
here they're little tails wag like dogs
they're so cute everything that moves on
the island really
should be seen as a potential source of
food and that includes the pigs
[Music]
keep in mind that these women have
basically had no food for over a week
and they are in a situation where they
could die of starvation
it's not just that but also the fact
that you get weak when you don't eat
after a few days
which makes every activity more and more
dangerous
with that said instead of turning those
pigs into food
they befriend them they sleep with the
pigs they feed the pigs
they comb the pig's hair they turn them
into pets and name them
sage and onion they pretty much do
everything with the pigs
except eat them then even worse
they determine that the beach that they
were on wasn't that great so they moved
to another beach
and they leave the pigs at the old beach
look at those we look like savannahs the
editor must have been laughing
uncontrollably when he put the clip of
them leaving the pigs
followed by one of them saying we look
like survivors
it wasn't me who did that i just trimmed
out a few seconds
but wait there's more they leave the
pigs on the old beach
the pigs follow them to the new camp and
they still
don't eat the pigs this whole situation
reminded me of when i did that video on
naked and afraid about cassie and
forrest
i only covered that one episode of the
show but i watched two seasons
of it to know what a typical episode
looks like a very common problem on that
show was that the women would refuse to
kill animals to eat
even if they weren't vegetarian keep in
mind that if you go on naked and afraid
you're supposed to be a survival expert
well at least in the first two seasons
they were supposed to be
so even the trained women will commonly
refuse to do the work to provide the
food they have no
problem with buying at the store in a
fancy package
the women on the island were the same
way the fate of sage and onion
hangs in the balance the women have
befriended them
and now can't agree whether or not to
eat them
i am hungry i don't think i could look
into his little piggy eyes
and then kill him at this point in the
show the men had to run out
and go find their food they were able to
successfully capture a crocodile
while the women had food just walk up to
them and they were unwilling to do what
it takes to survive
and i think this brings up an
interesting point that holds a lot of
people back
this happens everywhere but i see it on
youtube all the time so that's the
example i'm going to go with
youtubers will say things like i don't
want to create interesting titles
that's click bait look that's fine but
have fun getting like one tenth of the
viewers because your title isn't good
and i literally mean that a bad title
will harm you that much
not to mention there are plenty of ways
to make good titles without lying to
your viewers
but that's a skill that you have to
practice not putting the work in to
learn how to attract an audience
says to me that you don't want to put
the time in or make the sacrifices it
takes to be successful
if you are going to survive on an island
where there aren't enough plants to
sustain you
then you need to hunt or you will die
none of the women were willing to kill
except for lauren the nurse everyone but
lauren and jamie who was a vegetarian
and only eight plants
should be ashamed of themselves for
eating meat without being willing to do
the dirty work themselves
so lauren does eventually kill the two
piglets and the women finally get to eat
except for jaime the vegetarian now
there are some questions that people had
about the show
that i certainly have as well for
example
how exactly do two domesticated pigs
just suddenly walk up onto the women's
camp without a care in the world
when the women were starving also
curious
there were two piglets from an earlier
scene the women found by chance
but ignored because their mom was around
and they were afraid of being attacked
however just a few minutes later into
the episode
two very similar looking piglets show up
without a mom to protect them
that's very questionable but i don't
have any evidence to say that the
producers released those pigs to help
out the women
however bear grylls admitted that the
show stocked the island with different
animals
so everything there wasn't entirely
native but then
people also found it strange that this
fully grown pig
was just laying out there in the open
not caught in a trap
perfectly fine with a bunch of people
walking up to it
you see it
[Music]
a hunting party led by lauren has
stumbled across a sleeping pig
in the middle of the jungle
[Music]
people were saying that the pig was
drugged and that's why the women were
able to catch it
but i have a different explanation for
why it put up so little resistance
later the women found out that the pig
was full of ticks
the pig was probably half dead when they
tried to capture it which is why i
didn't make much of an effort to run
away
so i will give the women credit for
catching that one however
this leads us to our third crisis
outside of their camp
now being infested with ticks for some
reason the women decide to preserve the
pig leftovers in one of their water
canisters
and bury it underground this didn't work
and all the women got sick the next day
from eating rotten meat
except for jaime the vegetarian it's at
this point they make their most
disastrous screw-up
that would have killed everyone if the
emergency medical team didn't help them
the women took the water canister which
was full of rotten pig
and instead of trying to sanitize it
they threw it away
with the preserved pork no longer edible
the women removed the pig's remains
and jerry canner putrid meat from the
camp unconvinced they could salvage a
rancid jerrycan
and use it to purify the water again the
women
throw it away now with only one jerrycan
to produce
all their water the women are
unknowingly heading towards a
dehydration
crisis what were they thinking this
messed up their entire filtration system
and cut the amount of water they could
produce in half
the women used one canister to filter
the water and one canister to boil it
by the way speaking of the man they had
a far more sophisticated water
filtration system than the women did
that resulted in cleaner water and the
men
never seemed to have a problem with
dehydration
i don't want to drink the water
and drink it then you go
and then you vomit have you learned to
hate drinking
warm water actually it's good
it's really good it's sauces you don't
have to kind of just knock it back it's
decent water
the water was not an issue yeah and
actually dehydration was your own fault
rather than lack of water
so the women threw away their water
canister which have their water supply
and now they're all dehydrated really
how hard is it to wash the container out
in the ocean let it air out in the sun
and boil water in it to kill the rest of
the bacteria
you've been boiling water to kill
bacteria the entire time you've been on
the island
a little while later all the women
almost died and had to be saved by the
medical team
this medical visit came with the
extremely obvious advice which was
telling the women to sanitize the dirty
canister
you can hear the medical team's eyes
rolling when they say this
your bodies are just starting to fail at
this point
now there's no easy way to say this um
i'm teetering
right on the brink of pulling you all
off the island
for medical reasons the solution
is use the other jury can i can't
say it any other way so the women don't
die of dehydration
and later in the episode one of the
women gets a random ship that passes by
to give her a free fish
you have fish
one fish he's gonna throw it oh you're
very very kind
whoa now i think
that is a barracuda we got a face
yeah oh my god
okay that's totally not cheating now
another thing you will notice if you
watch this season
by the way it's season two and it's free
if you have amazon prime
but if you watch it you will see that
one of the big problems that women have
is laziness i think someone forgot to
tell them that this is survival you are
supposed to work from the time the sun
comes up
until the sun goes down and you can't
see anymore if you watch the men
they barely had any down time or vast
periods of slacking off
until the last day but with the women
barra's first perception of them
was that they were too busy chatting
instead of moving forward
you know it's four o'clock it's gonna
get dark here in a couple of hours
and already you know they've been 15
minutes chat
chat on the beach they need to work hard
get moving that
wasn't just a problem they had on the
first day here's more slacking off from
the women
2pm julie is still fishing whilst the
rest of the women
are more interested in sunbathing and
relaxing on the beach
this is why we came here this bay is an
absolute dream isn't it
beth and lauren wake to discover none of
the other women have done any work
stayed up we cooked breakfast for
everybody we cooked supper for everybody
and then we needed a kind of a little
bit of a break today and because we've
had a break everybody else has had a
break and nothing's happened
keep in mind that the previous clip
comes from the same episode where they
were all dying of dehydration
and it continues up until the final week
here is belinda the doctor splashing
around in the water with jamie
instead of working when everyone is
starving and dehydrated
while the rest of the group toil away on
the bed shelter
[Applause]
jamie and belinda decide to take the
afternoon off
[Music]
[Applause]
after watching the show my thought was
that they wouldn't have had half of the
problems they did
if they just worked harder that and my
final point
which was that there was zero leadership
on the women's island whatsoever
from day one the women have governed
themselves in the leaderless community
trying to make group decisions what was
there not enough wood have you ran out
of wood now
we ran out of wood last night and
everyone went you're joking there's no
leader not one person rules the roost
we work collectively so we say
i want to go foraging i don't have to be
told to go foraging
i'm going to go foraging all the
decisions we've made thus far have been
made collaboratively not needed to
conform to
a system where as a leader so how's that
working for you
my understanding is that you have almost
died twice
as i said being independent and doing
whatever you want is a luxury
afforded to you by living in a first
world country
you need leadership and you need someone
to set goals for the group
even if those goals aren't that great
it's better that you're working towards
something
rather than working towards nothing and
of course lesser goals can always be
tossed out as better ones are found
however the women were rather good at
doing nothing
partially because they had no direction
and they should have decided on a leader
right away both the men and the women
failed to do that within the first few
days as for the men
although it wasn't really talked about i
believe they eventually
established will the guy who ruptured
attendant and had to be evacuated
as their leader leaders decide on goals
and you need to have a goal to run a
functioning group
you need to have goals to run a
functioning life you can't just
follow your bliss and only forage when
you want to forage
survival and success are about getting
yourself to do a bunch of things
you don't want to do not about doing
whatever you want when it's convenient
for you to do so
the second thing leaders do especially
if they are smart
is divide labor so that people are set
in the roles they are best at
you have 14 people but you don't need 14
fishers
someone has to fish someone has to
collect water someone has to keep the
fire alive
and someone has to build shelter it's up
to the leader to decide
who is best to handle those jobs last
leaders are there to handle conflict and
ensure people get along
conflict will kill a group which
surprisingly was pretty well displayed
in the first episode of the men's island
as it caused one of their very useful
builders to leave
remember i did say the men had their
struggles too though conflict was a
pretty big problem on the women's island
as well
eventually the women come to their
senses and make lauren the leader
to me lauren was the clear choice
because she says things
like this i will not let people see that
i'm feeling just as weak as them because
i actually feel like some people need
strength in other people to keep them
going and i'm determined to be that
person
personally i think this is one of the
few good decisions
that the women made a leader is the
person who goes first
that's why it's called a leader they
lead lauren
was the first to kill an animal so they
could all eat when no one else wanted to
actually outside of a few fish at the
very end i don't remember
any of the women except for lauren
killing anything for food
lauren was also the only one on the team
who had
any meaningful survival experience in a
podcast recorded over a year after the
show was filmed
lauren states that she joined a
competition to row across the atlantic
ocean
where she was stuck in a boat with one
friend for over three months
about a month of that was just them
trying to survive while they were
waiting for help
because their boat broke she didn't
finish the race but she went back after
the island and did the race again
and got second place it takes a heavy
amount of grit to do that
anyway things immediately got better
once the women established a leader and
they actually started getting stuff done
in the last week also for some reason
they chose this person beth as a leader
too
but as far as what we can see on the
show lauren pretty much did all the work
leading
so now we are at the end of the show the
men made it on the island for six weeks
and the women sort of made it on the
island for six weeks
i did however find it funny that both
groups went right to gender stereotypes
the men were primarily focused on
hunting for food
while the women were primarily focused
on gathering
at the end of the six weeks each team
showed off their camps to bear grylls
the men's camp was very utilitarian
while the women's camp was very
decorated and made over one more thing
the women slept communally while the men
slept individually
so this show turned out to be a real win
for feminism
on breaking gender stereotypes by the
way there were more examples on them
conforming to stereotypes
than the ones i gave another win for
feminism
is that ruth england called season one
of the show sexist
because only men were allowed on that
season she said it portrayed the notion
that women needed to be helped to
survive well
seeing that the women almost died twice
throughout the six weeks and
almost had their team member fran die in
the first week i don't see how ruth
england's notion that average women can
survive without men
is proven so many people watched that
first series
and said oh you know women would have
done much better they would have
multitasked they wouldn't have had the
ego
still the show went to great lengths at
the end to make the women seem better
than they were
if i hadn't turned up today and i turned
up in six months
i bet these guys would be in pretty good
shape and i knew it
i knew the stereotype was wrong you know
but i knew they could nail this wow the
pandering is strong here
there is no way they would have made it
six months
how about this what if we just accepted
that men and women have certain
limitations
and moved on with our lives now for this
last part i want to talk a little bit
about the men
they didn't have much drama but there
was one really interesting episode the
men had
that i think brings up something very
valuable to say this euphemistically
the men's team had some very strong
personalities
as i said before one member paul left
the island because he couldn't get along
with another team member who
also ended up leaving the island vic who
manages a cleaning company
also had a strong personality which made
him very judgmental of the people he
felt were slacking off
they actually created three episodes out
of this based on vic
probably because it was the only drama
they had on the men's island
in one of the episodes vic has a dispute
with one of the cameramen
sam unlike naked and afraid the
cameraman have to participate in the
game too
also side note there were two sams and
this is a different sam from the one i
mentioned earlier who got lost
that being said sam's value to the group
is very abstract
because sam is creative the unfortunate
truth
is that generally the majority of
creative people
don't produce anything useful however if
you don't have any creative people
your society will falter to the ones
that do in this regard
there are two things that have to happen
in a functioning group or a functioning
person
one you have to repeat patterns and
strategies that work
and two you have to discover new
patterns and strategies that are more
effective
and less time consuming than the old
ones so if the men's team wants to be
effective
they need to do the daily chores but
they also need to be venturing out into
the island to discover a new territory
they need to be trying new tricks they
need to be inventing new technologies
and they need to learn how to scale
their economy
this is where sam the useless
daydreaming cameraman
comes in sam reportedly doesn't work
hard
unless he is really interested in the
idea that idea
is a fishing net the net was something
they found amongst all the trash that
washed up on shore
they found a lot of items that way
people saw the fishing net as a waste of
time because it failed previously but
against everyone's wishes
sam goes to work on the net in an
attempt to catch more fish
he fails now released from wood duty
sam sets off to check his nets i'm very
positive despite the group's hostility
sam's convinced his nets will work i
refuse pessimism to seep in
absolutely optimism it is then as
optimum as it is
nothing very predictable it's a waste of
energy
time fuel everything stop
fighting around and start doing
something worthwhile vic gets mad about
sam's failure
and treats him even worse than before
this is a
big deal because vic is one of the most
valuable members on the team
especially when it comes to collecting
food however
sam refuses to fall online and continues
to work on the fishing net
despite the failure and that makes vic
even more mad
big no do you trust me
i would never trust a stranger i'm a
stranger at first you were
okay it's taking me longer to get used
to you
than it has any other guys because they
sound a little bit like me
so unfortunately i don't trust you yeah
interesting
vic is mad because he doesn't like
politicians and he says that sam sounds
like a politician
rather than someone who is working class
like he is but there is one thing that's
for certain which is that creativity
requires tons of trial and error
and tons of failure failure is a part of
the process
of learning new things the problem is
that in survival
failure has harsh consequences however
eventually everyone gets desperate
because there's no food and they run to
help sam with the nets
if you catch something fishy nets
require more than one person to pull
them out of the ocean
and well this time sam succeeds
[Applause]
there's a lot of whooping cough people
all i wanted was just a fish one fish
how many fishes have we got
is the most successful fisher in the
group and has saved the day
many times when people were hungry at
best i believe
vic caught six fish in one day in this
case
sam caught 21 fish in one day while
expending
way less energy and time than vic would
have used catching that many fish
here is vic being a good sport about it
admitting he was wrong
and letting sam know that he has earned
his respect
some determination determination's been
amazing with m ned i'm really happy that
you can see that
yes i couldn't i won't deny it i
couldn't see it at all
i just thought well you're a big city
fanny but uh
the big city fan has done good sam
farmer my outcomes off to you sir well
done you for having the balls and the
determination to fix them every time
because that's certainly worth my cup of
tea at all
so vic learns the value of creativity
and this is why
although often annoying and seemingly
useless
creative people are needed if you can
afford creativity through excess
resources or time
it can be one of the most valuable
components of your group or your society
i think it also shows why no matter who
you are you need
some creativity in your life you don't
have to be a full-on inventor
but if you want a lot of success you
can't just play the same game
every single day you have to spend time
learning new skills and discovering
new ways to market those skills you also
have to work hard
be willing to take risks and accept that
a ton of failure is a part of the
process
if you don't do those things don't
complain about how everyone else is
successful
while you aren't if your strategies
don't work
you need to find new strategies there's
a second lesson in this episode
that i think is valuable because a lot
of people are looking for acceptance
if you watch the episode you can see how
sam is on thin ice with most of the
group
but then a few moments later they are
cheering his name
he got everyone to like him and he did
that by being
useful this is something that a lot of
people
are missing if you want to have friends
if you want to have people like you
if you want to have people respect you
the primary way you earn that is by
being productive
and providing value to other people if
you don't provide value to anyone
people aren't going to like you well
maybe that's inaccurate
the only people who will like you are
people who also don't provide any
particular amount of value
so you'll have friends who are worthless
if you have friends at all
if you want to change that you need to
actually produce something
you need to be useful
and with that sentiment i think this
video has gone on long enough
so if you liked it hit the like button
subscribe if you're new
comment and share if you would like to
support this channel
then you can do so with paypal patreon
or subscribe star
you can find all those links in the
description
last if you haven't checked me out on
bit shoot or parlor
you can also find those links in the
description otherwise
thanks for watching and i'll see you in
the next video